Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
Small Magellanic Cloud
Outskirts
<Hit!>
<We've created an opening in the enemy lines.>
<Divide the enemy.>
<The 7th Strike Group is to advance!>
<Drive a wedge through them!>
<Flatten them!>
This is Rear Brigadier Berger, 7th Strike Group.
Enemy is seventy percent eliminated. They're turning tail and running.
The Gatlantis are nothing to fear.
Don't underestimate our foe.
Y-Yes, sir.
The 7th Strike Group is to destroy the remaining hostiles.
Zar Balk!
Berger is getting cocky.
But this will keep them off our backs for a while.
You're going to miss the fun, aren't you?
That's right.
General Domel, message from Imperial Command.
From Baleras? Who is it?
Admiral Ditz, Supreme Commander of Astrofleets.
You look well.
I am pleased to see that you also do, sir.
Domel, you have been ordered to return to the home world.
You are to be awarded the Desler Cross, Special First Class.
I'm honored, sir. But this is the
lynchpin of the empire's defenses.
As commanding officer, I cannot leave the front lines for any such reason.
I understand. This is a political performance.
But His Lordship has some idea in mind.
I've sent the 8th Army as reinforcements.
And Gudell's Gross Space Armored Forces are on the way.
Leave the rest to them.
Understood.
Then I'll see you at Baleras.
Zar Balk!
The Milky Way Galaxy
You can get dressed, thank you.
Their DNA is arranged just like ours?
Right. She's the same as us. Except for her skin color.
Captain, we should be able to get more useful information out of Melda.
I can think of many ways to question her.
No, we should let her go.
Her ship has no warp drive. Interstellar flight is impossible.
We'll end up killing her.
But...
Cell #1
We can't just keep her locked up. She helped us escape.
In a way, she's one of us.
One of us?
Lots of people on board have lost family to the Garmillans!
Shouldn't we consider their feelings?
I have, as well!
My brother died fighting them. I hate them as much as anyone.
One reason to lock her up is to protect her from those feelings getting out of hand.
No one on this ship would do anything like that!
Your words are lacking in logic.
Better than lacking in humanity.
My decision remains unchanged.
I'll leave her questioning to you, Kodai.
Hey, can you believe what that Garmillan woman said?
What did she say?
That we attacked first.
Didn't you survive first contact, Yama? That wasn't what happened, right?
Yeah, that's a stupid lie.
My, my... The whole ship is talking about what that Garmillan said.
Yabu! Didn't you have to see Ms. Niimi for counseling?
Right. I'll be leaving early, then.
Are you feeling uncertain?
Earth in Danger
Official Government Material
Record of Our War Against the Aliens
The date is April 1, 2191.
An observation station on Uranus captures video of
spaceships from another civilization entering the Solar System.
The UN Cosmo Force immediately gathers the inner planet fleet.
The first defensive actions in our history against an enemy
Lunar Inner Planet Fleet Setting Out
from outside the Solar System are ordered.
Japanese Fleet Setting Sail from Fuji Spaceport
Twenty-seven Japanese battleships participate.
The fleet commander is Admiral Juzo Okita,
famous for his actions
Admiral Juzo Okita
during the Second Inner Planet War.
The first ship to encounter them in orbit
near Pluto is Japanese cruiser Murasame.
Your father isn't going to fight.
I'm sure we can be friends with the aliens.
Really?
Yes, hold on to hope.
But without warning, the aliens
open fire on the Murasame, destroying it.
With the exception of one crew member who is rescued,
Captain Daigo Shima and all crew perish, becoming the first casualties in this war.
Captain Daigo Shima, Killed in Battle
That's my father.
They fired first! Cowardly... Sneaky...
Without hesitating at the thought of destroying humanity.
The Garmillans are demons with human faces!
To me and to Kodai, they are enemies we can never forgive.
We must stand against a greater threat than any we have ever known!
Your father was a great man. I can swear to that.
Thank you.
We must never forgive these demonic invaders from outer space!
I've been asked to interrogate you.
Look at that. Let's see what he can do.
Oh, your shift isn't for another three hours.
I feel bad about what happened.
Lower Storm Leader Melda Ditz, serial number 3817529.
You have the same mentality we do.
The war movies I used to watch always had scenes like this.
Do you know what a movie is?
Do you have any treaties on POW treatment?
If you surrender to us, you will be treated fairly.
But if you refuse, you will be wiped out.
That's why you tried to destroy Earth? Is that your way?
But we were able to work together. That's a fact.
We don't break our promises.
Nor do we.
But I have the feeling you and I can trust each other.
I'm sure the XO will say I'm not being logical again, though.
Is this an interrogation?
You have to build trust first.
I hope he doesn't get any closer than he needs to.
The Tactical Officer is a man, after all.
Sharing trust with an alien is a fantasy.
After leaving the Milky Way, we'll be heading to Balun,
the midpoint between the Large Magellanic Cloud and us.
It's a lighthouse in space.
Navigation Officer, did Yamato Plan HQ name it Balun?
I'm told the name was in the plans Yurisha gave us a year ago.
Yamazaki.
Navigation Officer, may I have a word?
S-Sure.
You're working hard.
I don't mind exercising.
But trying too hard isn't good for you.
What do you mean?
Don't you think you're taking it too personal?
Want to go cheer up some?
What did you want to discuss?
I was on board the ship your father captained.
Command issued a gag order to me regarding what I'd like to tell you.
However, I'm going to violate that order.
We attempted peaceful contact.
But they attacked us nevertheless.
The UN Space Defense Committee took this as an act of aggression against Earth,
and it issued an emergency order...
Open fire, Okita!
This is humanity's first contact with
another civilization. This is too hasty.
What if we do nothing and it's too late? This is Central Command's decision!
Impossible.
Message from the Murasame, in the vanguard.
"We have encountered the alien ship. Requesting orders."
It appears there's no point in discussing things further.
Okita, by my authority as Military Director, I hereby remove you from command!
This is Serizawa from Central Command.
The Murasame is to open fire on the alien vessel immediately.
But Admiral Okita...
Has been removed from command!
This is an order!
And so we opened fire.
Deck 4 has been hit!
Critical damage! Second main gun is down!
Main engine output reduced by eighty percent!
All crew, abandon ship!
Abandon ship?
This ship is finished. Engine Officer,
head below and manage the evacuation.
B-But...
Friendship with the aliens is possible. I told my son that.
And instead, we...
Captain!
Go quickly! That's an order!
Yes, sir.
All crew, abandon ship! Go!
Emergency. Sealing airtight bulkheads.
Captain!
Daisuke, hold on to hope...
I don't remember what happened next.
Or how I escaped.
The battle had already ended.
And there was no sign of the comrades I'd thought had escaped with me.
That's a lie! You're lying!
So there you are.
Did you learn anything?
She's a person to whom honor means a great deal.
We won't be able to learn any more from her.
Those who close their eyes to the past become blind to the future.
I wonder who said that.
Do you enjoy insulting my father's honor?
The captain was a great man. That's why I wanted you to—
I refuse to accept it! I refuse!
Doesn't this feel great?
This is what you meant by "cheer up"?
Well, after exercise, you stretch and
have a bath. Everyone knows that, right?
It's a little surprising.
From what I hear about you all the time, I expected you to be more guarded.
That's a problem.
About before...
What is it that I'm taking too personal?
Does it seem that way?
A little.
I know you lost your brother fighting the Garmillans.
But it isn't fair to direct your anger toward her.
So that's it?
If you ever lose family in a war, you'll understand.
That might be difficult.
My only memories are from this past year.
I suppose my family is all dead, but I can't remember what they were like.
So...
Then I don't think you could understand.
Our investigation has revealed a high probability that there is
an enemy outpost in this star system that we'll pass through.
We've already decided a route around it.
No, we will maintain course.
And we will release Lower Storm Leader Ditz there.
Time for shift change.
I'm opposed to it. If she's a spy...
Shima?
My decision stands.
She's the kind of woman who lies and claims we attacked first!
What's wrong? This isn't like you.
You lost your brother, too! You don't really trust Melda, right?
Am I wrong?
This is the main bridge.
The Garmillas fighter that was on board has launched.
Who's on it?
It appears to be Melda.
She escaped.
One of the Falcons launched, too.
Did someone issue a pursuit order?
What?
This is the Yamato. Come in, Falcon!
I repeat, come in, Falcon!
Hey, who's piloting that thing? What do you plan to do?
Come in! Can you hear me?
It's just you and me out here.
Enemy lock-on.
Warning! Warning! Engine trouble!
Ship cannot maintain itself in these conditions.
Engine pressure rising. Critical in ten seconds.
Eject! Now!
Akio...
You're awake?
Where am I?
The Yamato. Melda brought you back.
Melda did?
Seriously...
She's leaving soon.
Yuki, I...
Six days in the brig.
Of course.
But I do think I feel better.
This is goodbye. There's food in here for four days.
You didn't think I might leave her and escape?
I think we can trust one another.
"You have talent."
Tell her that.
The Garmillas fighter will be launching shortly.
Guidance crew is to prepare for launch.
We really do have the same mentality.
Repeat, guidance crew is to prepare for launch.
Change course. We're leaving the area.
Roger.
Episode 11
A World I Once Saw
Believe that
Only the future
Has the answer
No one knows
Memory only strikes at
The heart to find
The truth
Do not forget it…
Many stars lie beyond
The spiral of memory
Sparkling in what looks like
The light of memory
Those who come from beyond the horizon.
Two worlds.
Truth and fact.
Two truths each create their own sense of "right."
Is there any hope to be found beyond them?
The Yamato presses forward, across the galactic seas.
Next time: What Lies Beyond.
There are 318 days left before humanity is extinct.